Hello friends, I am Umesh Kumar. You are watching
iNews
YouTube.
We are going to tell you how insurance is done.
In the previous video, we told you how
you
can insure Bajaj and HDFC through CSC. If you
want to insure all these companies, you can insure Bajaj
and HDFC ERGO.
You will find the video in the description
and you will watch the video. Today,
in this video, we will show you how to insure your
bike through ICICI Lombard. So
friends, let's
start the video. First of all,
we will login to the CSC portal and
enter our ID and password.
After that, see, we have to
click on the insurance tab because we are going to
insure the bike now. So,
click on the insurance tab.
After clicking, you will
see something like this here. If you look here, you will find '
Motor Third Party' written at the
bottom because you have to do third party insurance.
You will see many companies here. So,
today we are going to insure our bike through ICICI
Lombard
General Insurance. Let's go
here.  Let us show you, see
here
we have clicked on ICICI Lombard, if you
see in the first, two wheeler is written, it is
ticked, so
you have to tick on two wheeler TP i.e. third party,
after that if you are new then you will
click on policy for new vehicle,
if you want to renew then
you will click on second option, after that you will
click on get quit,
now if you see here then
you have to fill the registration details here, that is the
registration number of the vehicle, you will type it here,
after that click on get RTO details,
if the details are not available then you have to
fill it manually, like
which state
is it here, which state does the bike have to be insured,
you will
select it here, like if it is Jharkhand here then
Jharkhand is selected here,
after that first registration date i.e.
when was the vehicle purchased, when was it purchased,
you will select that date here, which is
given in the owner book, which is the
owner book of the vehicle, you will get it in it, so
from there you will select the date here,
as soon as you select the date, you will see
here  But you will see that your policy
start date is starting from now, that is, it starts from the
date from when you are doing it.
If you want to change it, you
can change it from here, but we have to start from the same day on which
we are doing the policy.
We have to start the
policy for one year from that day. We will keep the date of the same day on
which we are doing the policy, if we are doing it on the
4th date, then the
date is given here.
After that, look here below, you will see the
manufacturer, that is, which company's
bike is it, whether it is Honda, Bajaj, TVS, RO,
whichever company your bike belongs to,
you will tick on that company here. Let's
tick it here.
After that, look here, you will select the model number
here, how many cc it is,
you will also see that here. Whatever
model of your bike is, you
will select it here, it is Mera Dream New, so you have
selected it here. Now, the
details of some cover are given here, if you
want to take insurance cover or something, then
you will tick on this or personal
accident cover or whatever you want to take.  If yes,
you will see it and tick it and
click on Get Quit.
After that, see here friends,
as soon as you click on Get Quit,
you will not feel any red color here. You can
see the red color arrow on this.
Where was this registration done on this? From which RTO?
From where was the bike purchased?
You have to enter the name of that city here. So let's enter the
name of the city on this. For example, if Bokaro
is from Jharkhand, then let's select Bokar Jharkhand here.
Now if we click on Get Quit here again, then
whatever premium I have to pay for
third party insurance, it will be visible to you here.
Let's see here, the
premium is Rs 887. So let's
click on Proceed here.
After clicking on Proceed, you will
see here that you can fill some details here,
like if you want to give other vehicle details, then you
can give it here. Like,
you will have to give the engine number here
and you will also have to give the chassis number. So,
let's fill the engine number and chassis
number here.  You will find the vehicle in the owner book and fill
it from there.
After filling it, you will see that
you will find the chase number in the owner book,
you will fill the chase number here as well and
select whatever your body type is, if you
want to give anything else then you can give it here
and add nominee details, if you
want to add a nominee then click on add nominee
details, then you will
see the option to add a nominee, so here you will
enter the name of the nominee and what is the relationship, what is the
relationship with the bike owner, you will
type it
and what is his age, you have to fill it here,
so let's fill all the details here,
after that you will see create new customer, it is
given below, in this whoever
is the owner of the bike, if he is the owner of the car, then
his name is given in the owner book, so
you have to give the name here, so let's type the name here,
after typing the name you have to type his date of
birth also,
so see, the name which has been entered in the owner book here,
whatever date of birth of the customer is,
enter it here  After entering it,
you have to enter his address as well, so
let's fill the date of birth correctly here,
in the address, you will also find your address in the owner book,
if you have two addresses,
fill both the addresses here,
after filling, if there is a landmark, then
enter that as well,
so let's fill all the details here,
after that see if the pin code is done,
enter the area pin code here, after entering the pin code, the
city and state will
automatically appear here, if it is correct then fine,
now see, you can also enter the email ID below,
so let's enter an email ID here too,
so friends, here you
can enter the customer's email ID, if not, then you
can enter your email ID as well,
after that see, you have to type a mobile number, you will
type the
customer's mobile number here, after typing the customer's mobile number,
if the customer has a PAN number, then
enter the PAN number here, otherwise leave it, after that
you will click on generate proposal, so
friends, let's click here,
so see, the total premium is visible to you on this,
click on buy now
After that the payment page will open, where
payment has to be made through CSC,
so as soon as the payment page opens,
you will see here that the premium
is
887 and 828 will be deducted from the wallet,
so type the CSC password
here,
after typing the CSC password we will have to validate it,
friends, you get some commission in this also,
as you will see here
that
887 has to be taken from the customer and 828 will be
deducted from your wallet, so let's enter the wallet PIN here
and click on pay, as
soon as you click on pay, the payment becomes
successful, after the payment is successful,
you can download your insurance slip from here,
you will click on download,
after clicking you will see that it will
start downloading below,
so see this type of
PDF file has been downloaded here, you
can open it and see that the policy is
ready for the customer, you can print it and
give it to the customer,
friends, if you liked this video then
like and share it.
To watch similar videos, keep subscribing to the channel and also
press the bell icon so that
you can get new updates. We will meet
in the next video, till then Jai Hind
Vande Mataram.